<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on ARES/RACES of Mountain View, CA</title>
    <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on ARES/RACES of Mountain View, CA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emergency Communications Training</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/training/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s Missing  Flow chart of SCCo classes Drills, exercises, nets CERT  Local Training and Presentations Training sessions are offered locally by our Emergency Coordinator and Assistant Emergency Coordinators. They focus on subjects specific to Mountain View, such as message passing in a CERT environment and operations in the Radio Room in the Mountain View Fire and Police administration building at 1000 Villa St. Classes are listed on the Calendar page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call Sign Practice</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/call-sign-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 14:30:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/call-sign-practice/</guid>
      <description>Donna Gandour, KK6LUA, has made 5 short audio recordings of call signs slowly announced phonetically in groups that follow the same manner used for our Monday night nets. You can listen to the recordings and practice writing down the call signs, and if you wish, also check them off on the pre-formatted log sheet also linked below.
Click on a link to hear call signs in each group:
 🔊Call Signs for AECs 🔊Call Signs A-F 🔊Call Signs G-L 🔊Call Signs M-S 🔊Call Signs T-Z  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Net Signup</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/net-signup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 14:30:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/net-signup/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newcomers</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/newcomers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 14:30:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/newcomers/</guid>
      <description>Qualifications Experience and Training Mountain View ARES/RACES provides opportunities for licensed ham radio operators to increase their skills and knowledge in communication networks and emergency preparedness.
There are several types of opportunities available for newcomers to gain experience in network communications, outlined below.
Weekly Nets Every Monday night Mountain View ARES/RACES members participate in a local city &amp;ldquo;net&amp;rdquo; that&amp;rsquo;s part of the weekly SPECS Net. During a net, participants tune their radios to the same frequency and listen to a &amp;ldquo;net control&amp;rdquo; operator read announcements and ask participants to check-in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 14:30:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/resources/</guid>
      <description>Mountain View ARES/RACES Emergency Plan The Mountain View ARES Emergency Plan (2019-11-24), describes procedures, resources, contact persons, and activation procedures to be followed in the event of an emergency.
Frequency Lists for Programming Radios Santa Clara Co. Frequencies&amp;mdash;These frequencies are organized by City in Santa Clara County and were prepared by Jerry Haag (SK) to match the order of frequencies programmed into the radios in the ARES shack in Mountain view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staff</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 14:30:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/staff/</guid>
      <description>Mountain View ARES/RACES Staff Mountain View ARES/RACES&amp;hellip; is an all volunteer team of more than 70 men and women. We are FCC-licensed amateur radio operators that provide emergency communications for the City of Mtn. View and local agencies as a public service. During 2019, ARES volunteers contributed over 4,000 hours of time to support city and county activities. We do what we do because we enjoy it! If you live in Mountain View and have an amateur radio license, come join us!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is ARES/RACES?</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/ares-races/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 14:30:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/ares-races/</guid>
      <description>ARES/RACES in Santa Clara County ARES and RACES originated as separate organizations both focused on providing emergency communications. ARES, the Amateur Radio Emergency System, is sponsored by the Amateur Radio Relay League (ARRL) and provides local and regional communications support to government and non-government agencies such as the Red Cross and National Weather Service during emergencies. RACES, the Radio Amateur Civil Emergency Service, was established by the FCC. Amateur radio operators that are registered with local, state, or federal government emergency agencies provide communications assistance during civil emergencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday Night Nets</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/nets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/nets/</guid>
      <description>Mountain View ARES/RACES participates in several nets on Monday nights:
SPECS Net: Every Monday Night, 20:00-20:30 The Southern Peninsula Emergency Communications System (SPECS) meets every Monday night at 20:00 (8:00 PM). SPECS conducts two nets on Monday nights, plus a concurrent set of city-specific nets; there&amp;rsquo;s an optional weekly packet practice as well:
  The optional &amp;ldquo;UHF net&amp;rdquo; meets from 19:30 to 20:00 on the linked W6ASH repeater UHF frequencies of 224.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Action Report: May, 2020 City/County Communications Drill</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/after-action-20200516/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/after-action-20200516/</guid>
      <description>Overview          Description Mountain View County/City Communications Drill   Event Date May 16, 2020   Duration 10:00 am to 12:00 noon   Location Remote&amp;mdash;operators&#39; homes   Debrief Zoom conference at 12:00 noon   Activation Number MTV-20-02T   Submitted by Leslie Grimm, ARES Emergency Coordinator    Description The scenario was a pandemic with shelter-in-place guidance. Our city’s health and safety officer was requesting information on mask usage and Covid-19 testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City-Wide Radio Reception Survey Study</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/survey-study-20200420/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/survey-study-20200420/</guid>
      <description>In order to both support operations during the COVID-19 shelter-at-home directive, and to help plan how to optimize future communications activities, during the four weeks from March March 23 through April 13, 2020, Mountain View ARES/RACES staff conducted a test of our ability to hear each other from our home locations during our regular monday night check-in nets.
What We Did During check-ins, participating operators recorded how well they could hear the others who were checking in using a simple coding scheme:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain View ARES/RACES 2020 Events Calendar</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/calendar/</guid>
      <description>JanuarySat Jan 040900-1200County&amp;mdash;Field Operations Type III, Part AWed Jan 081900-2100REACT MeetingCANCELLED Sat Jan 110900-1200SPECS General MeetingSat Jan 181000-1200MTV&amp;mdash;Antenna partyTue Jan 212030-2115County&amp;mdash;Training Net - Message Passing PracticeWed Jan 221000-1200County&amp;mdash;Santa Clara County EOC OrientationFebruarySat Feb 010900-1200County&amp;mdash;Net Control - Type III, Part AWed Feb 051900-2100REACT MeetingThu Feb 061900-2100CERT Refresher&amp;mdash;CERT Tools for Leadership SuccessSat Feb 080900-1200County&amp;mdash;Field Operations Type III, Type IISat Feb 080900-1200County&amp;mdash;Introduction to Emergency Communications - CupertinoTue Feb 182030-2115County&amp;mdash;Training Net - Message Passing PracticeSat Feb 221000-1300MTV/County&amp;mdash;ARES/RACES Communications DrillMarchWed Mar 041900-2100REACT MeetingSat Mar 070800-1800CERT Academy 2020-S (Spanish) March 7 and 14CANCELLED Sat Mar 070900-1200County&amp;mdash;Net Control - Type III, Part BCANCELLED Sat Mar 140900-1200County&amp;mdash;Fundamentals of Emergency Communications, CupertinoCANCELLED Tue Mar 172030-2115County&amp;mdash;Training Net - Message Passing PracticeSat Mar 210900-1200County&amp;mdash;Pop-Up Net Control PracticeCANCELLED Wed Mar 250800HospitalNet&amp;mdash;Statewide Medical Health Exercise (SWMHE)CANCELLED Sat Mar 280900-1200MTV&amp;mdash;Packet Lite ClassCANCELLED AprilWed Apr 011000-1200County&amp;mdash;Santa Clara County EOC OrientationCANCELLED Wed Apr 011900-2100REACT MeetingCANCELLED Thu Apr 021830-2130CERT Academy 2020-1 Tue &amp;amp; Thu nights, finish Saturday Feb 18CANCELLED Sat Apr 040900-1000County&amp;mdash;Net Control - Type IICANCELLED Sat Apr 041000-1200County&amp;mdash;Repeater Sprint Contest and PracticeSat Apr 041300-1345County&amp;mdash;Special Edition Message Passing Practice NetSat Apr 180900-1200CERT Refresher&amp;mdash;CERT Terrorism AwarenessCANCELLED Tue Apr 212030-2115County&amp;mdash;Training Net - Message Passing PracticeSat Apr 250800-1100REACT/ARES&amp;mdash;MTV City Parade, Castro St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off-the-Grid Communications Exercise</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/off-grid-20200223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/off-grid-20200223/</guid>
      <description>In response to the county ARES Communication Exercise, Mountain View did an &amp;ldquo;off the grid&amp;rdquo; exercise where everyone, including operators in the Radio Room at K6MTV operated their systems off batteries. Some participants traveled to CERT sites and recovered hidden messages to transmit. Other participants used their home packet system operating on battery power to send/receive messages. Operators at K6MTV also responded to messages from the County. There were 14 participants (radio room 4, mobile field 4, home packet 6).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Action Report: February, 2020 City/County Communications Drill</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/after-action-20200222/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/after-action-20200222/</guid>
      <description>Overview          Description Mountain View County/City Communications Drill   Event Date February 22, 2020   Duration 10:00 am to 12:00 noon   Location 1000 Villa Radio Room and Fire Stations 1,2,4 and 5   Debrief 1000 Villa Radio Room at noon   Activation Number MTV-20-01T   Submitted by Leslie Grimm, ARES Emergency Coordinator    Description The scenario was a severe wind and rainstorm causing flooding and power outages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Antenna Party</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2020/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the 2020 Antenna Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save the Date: Antenna Party Jan 18, 2020</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/antenna-party-ann-20191223/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/antenna-party-ann-20191223/</guid>
      <description>A new year is almost upon us, and it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to look over your equipment to be sure you&amp;rsquo;ll be ready when you’re needed. Come to our annual Antenna Party Saturday, Jan. 18, from 10am to noon at 1000 Villa. We will have antenna and radio analyzers so you can find out how accurate your equipment is. There will be examples of Go-Kits to give you ideas on what you might want to include in your own kit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Mountain View ARES/RACES Newsletter</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/2019-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/2019-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>2019 has been a full year for our ARES members! Thanks to all of you, we have been able to report to the City and County ARES/RACES that Mountain View hams have invested over 4000 hours in city and county training, exercises, and community events. In 2019 our members participated in 4 Mountain View classes, 4 county exercises, 4 city events and 2 city-wide CERT exercises, plus attending county classes. It was a busy and productive year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PacFORMS Update for MV CERT</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/da-summary-20191106/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/da-summary-20191106/</guid>
      <description>These are instructions for adding the revised Mountain View DA Summary form to an existing installation of Outpost.
The current version of Outpost, Installer 145C, can be found here and this version or later should be installed on your computer before installing the files described below. The 145C installer results in a version of Outpost that reports &amp;ldquo;Version 3.3.0 c65&amp;rdquo; when run. The Damage Assessment Summary form is still in PacFORMS format and will remain that way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packet Class Lite Wrapup</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/packet-20190211/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/packet-20190211/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this class was to introduce Outpost Packet operation to hams new to packet with a two fold objective: Introduce Packet operation with the hope that they would contine training with the county classes and to provide them with enough skills with Outpost so that they could relieve a trained packet operator for a breif period of time during an exercise or real emergency.
The class had 14 attendees: 1 presenter, 4 instructor/mentors, 9 students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Antenna Party</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2019/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the 2019 Antenna Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike-Mike Drill Wrapup</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/mike-mike-20180818/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/mike-mike-20180818/</guid>
      <description>I want to thank Rick Van Mell, KI6PUR, for cordinating the Mike-Mike drill Saturday. There were a total of 18 people participating inclucing the 5 of us in the &amp;ldquo;shack&amp;rdquo;. Rick sent 84 emails inviting Mountain View hams to participate in the drill, so the response was somewhat dissapointing. However, those who took the time to send us one or more Mike-Mike reports did a great job. The reports were generally well distributed around Mountain View.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Antenna Party</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2018/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the 2018 Antenna Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jerry Haag Dedication</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/jerry-haag-dedication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/jerry-haag-dedication/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the dedication of a plaque commemorating Jerry Hagg&amp;rsquo;s vounteer contributions to the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creek Survey Drill</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/creek-survey-20170218/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/creek-survey-20170218/</guid>
      <description>On February 18, 2017, we participated in the county wide drill, and our drill was to do a survey of the Stevens and Permanente Creeks at prescribed survey locations and record the real status of the creeks. The goals were to report the status of the information via simplex and repeater radios to net control and take pictures up and down stream. Mountain View CERT members were invited to assist as observers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Antenna Party</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2017/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the 2017 Antenna Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jerry Haag, K6GAC</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/silent-keys/jerry-haag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/silent-keys/jerry-haag/</guid>
      <description>Jerry Haag died of a cerebral hemorrhage on April 11, 2016.
He served the community as our ARES/RACES EC for 15 years. He was also past president of the Fire Associates of Santa Clara Valley and a former Fire Inspector for the San Jose Fire Department.
A memorial service for Jerry Haag was held on Sunday, April 17, 2016 at 3 pm at Immanuel Lutheran Church, 1715 Grant Road in Los Altos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Antenna Party</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2016/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the 2016 Antenna Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 Antenna Party</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2015/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the 2015 Antenna Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June Welsh, KF6WPQ</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/silent-keys/june-welsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/silent-keys/june-welsh/</guid>
      <description>June Welsh, KF6WPQ, was a tireless volunteer for the Mountain View CERT Program and the Amateur Radio Emergency Service. For nearly 15 years she was the voice of the SPEC 220/440 net on Monday nights, and was the principle logistical support for the County ARES/RACES training sessions, for the SPECS annual meeting and the Flea Market. She will be sorely missed.
   0238 e
      596th</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 Antenna Party</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2013/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the 2013 Antenna Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2011 Antenna Party</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/antenna-2011/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the 2011 Antenna Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa Clara County Drill, July 18, 2009</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/county-drill-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/county-drill-2009/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the County drill held in July, 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Camino Hospital Emergency Drill, &#34;Garlic Powder&#34;</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/hospital-drill-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/hospital-drill-2007/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the El Camino Hospital drill held in June, 2007.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa Clara County Drill, April 23, 2005</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/county-drill-2005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/county-drill-2005/</guid>
      <description>Photos from the April, 2005 County drill, held at Mountain View Fire Station 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain View ARES/RACES Photos: 1990-1997</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/photos-1990-1997/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/photos/photos-1990-1997/</guid>
      <description>Some photos from the period from 1990 to 1997.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
