<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News, Events, and Training Activities on ARES/RACES of Mountain View, CA</title>
    <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News, Events, and Training Activities on ARES/RACES of Mountain View, CA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>After Action Report: May, 2020 City/County Communications Drill</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/after-action-20200516/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/after-action-20200516/</guid>
      <description>Overview          Description Mountain View County/City Communications Drill   Event Date May 16, 2020   Duration 10:00 am to 12:00 noon   Location Remote&amp;mdash;operators&#39; homes   Debrief Zoom conference at 12:00 noon   Activation Number MTV-20-02T   Submitted by Leslie Grimm, ARES Emergency Coordinator    Description The scenario was a pandemic with shelter-in-place guidance. Our city’s health and safety officer was requesting information on mask usage and Covid-19 testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City-Wide Radio Reception Survey Study</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/survey-study-20200420/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/survey-study-20200420/</guid>
      <description>In order to both support operations during the COVID-19 shelter-at-home directive, and to help plan how to optimize future communications activities, during the four weeks from March March 23 through April 13, 2020, Mountain View ARES/RACES staff conducted a test of our ability to hear each other from our home locations during our regular monday night check-in nets.
What We Did During check-ins, participating operators recorded how well they could hear the others who were checking in using a simple coding scheme:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off-the-Grid Communications Exercise</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/off-grid-20200223/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/off-grid-20200223/</guid>
      <description>In response to the county ARES Communication Exercise, Mountain View did an &amp;ldquo;off the grid&amp;rdquo; exercise where everyone, including operators in the Radio Room at K6MTV operated their systems off batteries. Some participants traveled to CERT sites and recovered hidden messages to transmit. Other participants used their home packet system operating on battery power to send/receive messages. Operators at K6MTV also responded to messages from the County. There were 14 participants (radio room 4, mobile field 4, home packet 6).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After Action Report: February, 2020 City/County Communications Drill</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/after-action-20200222/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/after-action-20200222/</guid>
      <description>Overview          Description Mountain View County/City Communications Drill   Event Date February 22, 2020   Duration 10:00 am to 12:00 noon   Location 1000 Villa Radio Room and Fire Stations 1,2,4 and 5   Debrief 1000 Villa Radio Room at noon   Activation Number MTV-20-01T   Submitted by Leslie Grimm, ARES Emergency Coordinator    Description The scenario was a severe wind and rainstorm causing flooding and power outages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save the Date: Antenna Party Jan 18, 2020</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/antenna-party-ann-20191223/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/antenna-party-ann-20191223/</guid>
      <description>A new year is almost upon us, and it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to look over your equipment to be sure you&amp;rsquo;ll be ready when you’re needed. Come to our annual Antenna Party Saturday, Jan. 18, from 10am to noon at 1000 Villa. We will have antenna and radio analyzers so you can find out how accurate your equipment is. There will be examples of Go-Kits to give you ideas on what you might want to include in your own kit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Mountain View ARES/RACES Newsletter</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/2019-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/2019-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>2019 has been a full year for our ARES members! Thanks to all of you, we have been able to report to the City and County ARES/RACES that Mountain View hams have invested over 4000 hours in city and county training, exercises, and community events. In 2019 our members participated in 4 Mountain View classes, 4 county exercises, 4 city events and 2 city-wide CERT exercises, plus attending county classes. It was a busy and productive year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PacFORMS Update for MV CERT</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/da-summary-20191106/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/da-summary-20191106/</guid>
      <description>These are instructions for adding the revised Mountain View DA Summary form to an existing installation of Outpost.
The current version of Outpost, Installer 145C, can be found here and this version or later should be installed on your computer before installing the files described below. The 145C installer results in a version of Outpost that reports &amp;ldquo;Version 3.3.0 c65&amp;rdquo; when run. The Damage Assessment Summary form is still in PacFORMS format and will remain that way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packet Class Lite Wrapup</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/packet-20190211/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/packet-20190211/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this class was to introduce Outpost Packet operation to hams new to packet with a two fold objective: Introduce Packet operation with the hope that they would contine training with the county classes and to provide them with enough skills with Outpost so that they could relieve a trained packet operator for a breif period of time during an exercise or real emergency.
The class had 14 attendees: 1 presenter, 4 instructor/mentors, 9 students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mike-Mike Drill Wrapup</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/mike-mike-20180818/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/mike-mike-20180818/</guid>
      <description>I want to thank Rick Van Mell, KI6PUR, for cordinating the Mike-Mike drill Saturday. There were a total of 18 people participating inclucing the 5 of us in the &amp;ldquo;shack&amp;rdquo;. Rick sent 84 emails inviting Mountain View hams to participate in the drill, so the response was somewhat dissapointing. However, those who took the time to send us one or more Mike-Mike reports did a great job. The reports were generally well distributed around Mountain View.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creek Survey Drill</title>
      <link>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/creek-survey-20170218/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://k6mtv.broadsky.net/news/creek-survey-20170218/</guid>
      <description>On February 18, 2017, we participated in the county wide drill, and our drill was to do a survey of the Stevens and Permanente Creeks at prescribed survey locations and record the real status of the creeks. The goals were to report the status of the information via simplex and repeater radios to net control and take pictures up and down stream. Mountain View CERT members were invited to assist as observers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
